$(document).ready(function() {
    cycleTestimonials(1,0);
    $('#start-btn').click(function() {   
        replaceHeading();
        $('#start').fadeOut(500, function() {
            newGame();
            findQuestion();
            loadQuestion();
            $('#quiz').fadeIn(500);
        });
        $('#testimonials').fadeOut(500);
        $('.disclaim').fadeOut(500);
    });
    $('#answer-btn').click(function() {
        var user_answer = $('input:radio[name=ans]:checked').val();
        if (!user_answer) {
            alert('Please make a selection!');
        } else {
            if (correct(user_answer)) {
                $('#quiz').fadeOut(500, function() {
                    score++;
                    updateScore();
                    $('.answer-exp').text(quiz_questions[num]["answer-exp"]);
                    $('#correct').fadeIn(500);    
                });
            } else {
                $('#quiz').fadeOut(500, function() {
                    $('.answer-exp').text(quiz_questions[num]["answer-exp"]);
                    $('#wrong').fadeIn(500);
                });
            }
        }
    });
    $('.cont-btn').click(function() {       
        $('#correct').fadeOut(500, function() {
            $('#wrong').fadeOut(500, function() {
                if (count >= count_limit) {
                    updateScore();
                    updateRank();
                    $('#final').fadeIn(500);
                } else {
                    findQuestion();
                    loadQuestion();
                    $('form input').prop('checked', false);
                    $('#quiz').fadeIn(500);
                }
            });
        });
    });
    $('#start-over').click(function() {       
        $('#final').fadeOut(500, function() {
            newGame();
            findQuestion();
            loadQuestion();
            $('form input').prop('checked', false);
            $('#quiz').fadeIn(500);    
        });
    });
});

var num = 0;
var count = 0;
var count_limit = 10;
var score = 0;
var prior_questions = [];

var replaceHeading = function() {
    var head = $("<span>The Time Travel Trivia Quiz</span>");
    $('h1').find("span").remove();
    $('h1').append(head);
};
var cycleTestimonials = function(index,prev) {
    $('#testimonials').children('p:eq(' + prev + ')').delay(1800).fadeOut(800, function(){
        $('#testimonials').children('p:eq(' + index + ')').fadeIn(800, function(){
            prev = index;
            if (index === 3){
                index = 0;
            } else {
                index++;
            }
            cycleTestimonials(index,prev);
        });
    });
};
var newGame = function() {
    num = 0;
    count = 0;
    score = 0;
    prior_questions = [];
};
var findQuestion = function() {
    pickQuestion();
    while (wasAsked()) {
        pickQuestion();
    }
};
var pickQuestion = function() {
    var limit = Object.keys(quiz_questions).length;
    num = Math.floor((Math.random() * limit) + 1)
};
var wasAsked = function() {
    var result = false;
    for (var i=0;i<=prior_questions.length;i++){
        if (num == prior_questions[i]) {
            result = true;
        }
    }
    return result;
};
var loadQuestion = function() {
    prior_questions.push(num);    
    $('#icon').html("<i class=\"fa fa-"+quiz_questions[num]["icon"]+"\"></i>");
    $('#text').html(quiz_questions[num]["question"]);
    $('#option-1').html(quiz_questions[num]["options"][1]);
    $('#option-2').html(quiz_questions[num]["options"][2]);
    $('#option-3').html(quiz_questions[num]["options"][3]);
    $('#option-4').html(quiz_questions[num]["options"][4]);
    $('#option-5').html(quiz_questions[num]["options"][5]);
    updateScore();
    count++;
    $('.progress').text(count+"/"+count_limit);
};
var correct = function(user_answer) {
    if (user_answer == quiz_questions[num]["answer"]) {
        return true;
    } else {
        return false;
    }
};
var updateScore = function() {
    $('.score').text(score);
};
var updateRank = function() {
    if (score == 10){
        $('.rank').text('Time Master');
        $('.rank-msg').text('Prefect score!)');
    } else if (score >= 7 && score <=  9) {
        $('.rank').text('Time Lord');
        $('.rank-msg').text('You have mad time travel trivia skillz! Time does your bidding, except for all that time you spent watching time travel movies - you can\'t get that back.');
    } else if (score >= 4 && score <= 6) {
        $('.rank').text('Time Traveler');
        $('.rank-msg').text('You may not be the best, but your not the worst.');
    } else if (score >= 1 && score <= 3) {
        $('.rank').text('Time Traveling Sidekick');
        $('.rank-msg').text('Meh. Not a great score, but if you ever ending up traveling through time you probably know enough to not accidently destroy the universe.');
    } else if (score == 0) {
        $('.rank').text('Time Dunce');
        $('.rank-msg').text('Doh! The only "time traveling" you apparently understand is starring at the clock while drool runs down your chin.');
    }
};
var quiz_questions = {
    1: {
        "icon": "book",
        "question": "In the movie <strong>Army of Darkness (1992)</strong>, the main character travels through time with several objects, which of the below items is NOT one of these items?",
        "options": {
            1: "A twelve-gauge double-barreled Remington",
            2: "A chemistry text book",
            3: "An S-Mart price gun",
            4: "An issue of Fangoria magazine",
            5: "An Oldsmobile Delta 88"
        },
        "answer": 3,
        "answer-exp": "In the movie, the main character Ash Williams travels through time in his Oldsmobile, uses his shotgun, and makes gunpowder using a chemistry textbook in the trunk of his car (when he gets the textbook, an issue of Fangoria can also be seen in his trunk). Although the main character works at a store called S-Mart, he doesn't have a price gun with him when he travels through time."
    },
    2: {
        "icon": "clock-o",
        "question": "Which of the below movies includes time travel as an element of the story?",
        "options": {
            1: "Once Upon a Time in America (1984)",
            2: "Nick of Time (1995)",
            3: "Same Time, Next Year (1978)",
            4: "Out of Time (1988)",
            5: "Wheel of Time (2003)"
        },
        "answer": 4,
        "answer-exp": "Out if Time (1988), which starred Bill Maher was a failed television pilot that was made into a television movie. The plot centered around a cop from 2088 who travels back to 1988 to pursue a criminal who escaped in a time machine, and enlists the aid of his great-grandfather (Maher)."
    },
    3: {
        "icon": "clock-o",
        "question": "Which of the following time travel movies is animated?",
        "options": {
            1: "Galaxis (1995)",
            2: "The Girl Who Leapt Through Time (2006)",
            3: "A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court (1949)",
            4: "New Adventures of a Yankee in King Arthur's Court (1988)",
            5: "G.I. Samurai (1979)"
        },
        "answer": 2,
        "answer-exp": "The Girl Who Leapt Through Time (2006) was an animated Japanese movie about a teenage girl, Makoto, who inadvertently gains the ability to leap through time. Makoto begins using the time-leaps to fix everyday problems of a teenager before realizing the source of her ability."
    },
    4: {
        "icon": "bolt",
        "question": "In the movie <strong>Back to the Future (1985)</strong>, how many gigawatts of electricity does it take to travel in time?",
        "options": {
            1: "9.21",
            2: "1.81",
            3: "10.31",
            4: "1.21",
            5: "2.21"
        },
        "answer": 4,
        "answer-exp": "In Back to the Future (1985), Dr. Brown's DeLorean needed to be traveling at 88 mph, and required 1.21 gigawatts of power. In vehicle originally had its power supplied by a plutonium-powered nuclear reactor."
    },
    5: {
        "icon": "male",
        "question": "Which of the following movies involves time travel without using a man-made device?",
        "options": {
            1: "About Time (2013)",
            2: "The Time Machine (1960)",
            3: "Source Code (2011)",
            4: "The Terminator (1984)",
            5: "Looper (2012)"
        },
        "answer": 1,
        "answer-exp": "In About Time (2013), the main character is informed by his father that the men in his family have the ability to travel through time at will. After reaching a certain age, they simply have to find a dark place and concentrate on a time (within their own life) to which they wish to travel."
    },
    6: {
        "icon": "ship",
        "question": "Which time travel movie involves a scene on the Titanic?",
        "options": {
            1: "Time After Time (1979)",
            2: "Time Bandits (1981)",
            3: "Time Travelers (1976)",
            4: "Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home (1986)",
            5: "Slipstream (2005)"
        },
        "answer": 2,
        "answer-exp": "In Time Bandits (1981), the band of time travelers briefly land aboard the RMS Titanic. While lounging on the ship one of them call out, \"Waiter! More Champagne and Plenty Of Ice.\" Shortly after the Titanic is hit by an iceberg."        
    },
    7: {
        "icon": "clock-o",
        "question": "The Canadian movie <strong>A Switch in Time (1989)</strong> was re-titled to capitalize on the success of <strong>Bill &amp; Ted's Excellent Adventure (1989)</strong>. What was the movie's new title?",
        "options": {
            1: "Norman's Awesome Experience",
            2: "Jim &amp; Billy's Great Journey",
            3: "Bob's Outstanding Journey in Time",
            4: "Nathan's Big Adventure, Ya Hosers!",
            5: "The Newf's Exceptional Escapade"
        },
        "answer": 1,
        "answer-exp": "Norman's Awesome Experience (1989) involves an American scientist, a fashion model, and her photographer who are accidentally transported back in time to the 1st Century A.D. in an area of present day Switzerland controlled by the Roman Empire."
    },
    8: {
        "icon": "beer",
        "question": "In the movie <strong>Frequently Asked Questions About Time Travel (2009)</strong>, a giant version of what appears outside the pub in the future?",
        "options": {
            1: "gerbel",
            2: "ferret",
            3: "ant",
            4: "caterpiller",
            5: "cockroach"
        },
        "answer": 3,
        "answer-exp": "In Frequently Asked Questions About Time Travel (2009), the main characters travel to a unknown future in which the pub they started in stands in ruins and the world outside is empty and desolate. They breifly hear a noise that makes them afraid which is revealed to be a giant ant."
    },
    9: {
        "icon": "car",
        "question": "In the movie <strong>Back to the Future (1985)</strong>, what was did the DeLorean's license plate read?",
        "options": {
            1: "HGWELLS",
            2: "MCFLY1",
            3: "DRBROWN",
            4: "OUTATIME",
            5: "88MPH"
        },
        "answer": 4,
        "answer-exp": "In Back to the Future (1985) the license plate of the time travelling DeLorean is shown to be \"OUTATIME.\" Images of the license plate with burning tire tracks was also used for many of the movie's posters."
    },
    10: {
        "icon": "calendar",
        "question": "In Stephen King's 2011 novel <strong>11/22/63</strong>, what event does the main character go back in time to try to prevent?",
        "options": {
            1: "U.S. involvement in Vietnam",
            2: "The release of the Beatles first album",
            3: "The assasination of J.F.K.",
            4: "The Cuban Missle Crisis",
            5: "The Apollo moon landing"
        },
        "answer": 3,
        "answer-exp": "The novel's main character, Jake Epping, discovers a diner that can take him back in time, but only to the same day in 1958. He ultimately decides to live in the past and wait for the events leadings up to President Kennedy's assasination on November 22, 1963 in an effort to prevent the event."
    },
    11: {
        "icon": "music",
        "question": "In the television show <strong>Life on Mars (UK 2006 &ndash; 2007)</strong>, what modern song does the main character hear that makes him think his 1970s reality might all be in his head?",
        "options": {
            1: "Boulevard Of Broken Dreams by Green Day",
            2: "Hey Ya! by OutKast",
            3: "Crazy by Gnarls Barkley",
            4: "Toxic by Brittney Spears",
            5: "Clocks by Coldplay"
        },
        "answer": 4,
        "answer-exp": "In the show's seventh episode, the main character (Sam), who is questioning his reality, briefly hears doctors' voices talking to him and the song \"Toxic\" by Britney Spears."
    },
    12: {
        "icon": "fighter-jet",
        "question": "In the movie <strong>The Final Countdown (1980)</strong>, what travels through time?",
        "options": {
            1: "a steam-powered train",
            2: "an aircraft carrier",
            3: "a passenger airplane",
            4: "a battleship",
            5: "a zeppelin"
        },
        "answer": 2,
        "answer-exp": "In The Final Countdown (1980), a modern aircraft carrier encounters a strange storm while out on a training mission. Entering the storm transports the carrier through time from 1980 to 1941, arriving the day before the attack on Pearl Harbor. The ships's captain must then decide whether to try to prevent the attack and change history."
    },
    13: {
        "icon": "history",
        "question": "In Michael Crichton's 1999 book <strong>Timeline</strong>, the characters travel to which period in time?",
        "options": {
            1: "13th Century France",
            2: "15th Century Spain",
            3: "14th Century Scotland",
            4: "13th Century Germany",
            5: "14th Century France"
        },
        "answer": 5,
        "answer-exp": "The story in Timeline involves a group of history students who travel to 14th Century France to rescue their professor."
    },
    14: {
        "icon": "history",
        "question": "Which television show included an episode in which a character goes back in time and saves Dr. Heimlich from choking - giving the doctor the idea for the Heimlich maneuver?",
        "options": {
            1: "Sliders (1995 &ndash; 2000)",
            2: "Journeyman (2007)",
            3: "Timecop (1997)",
            4: "Quantum Leap (1989 &ndash; 1993)",
            5: "The Time Tunnel (1966 &ndash; 1967)"
        },
        "answer": 4,
        "answer-exp": "In \"Thou Shall Not ...\", a 1989 episode of Quantum Leap (1989 - 1993), the main character (Sam) performs the Heimlich Maneuver on a choking man, who is later revealed to be Henry Heimlich - the inventor of the Heimlich Maneuver."
    },
    15: {
        "icon": "child",
        "question": "Which animated television show, featured time travel adventures, an anthropomorphic dog, and a girl from the future named Cupcake?",
        "options": {
            1: "The Fonz and the Happy Days Gang (1980 &ndash; 1982)",
            2: "Flint the Time Detective (1998 &ndash; 1999)",
            3: "Bill &amp; Ted's Excellant Adventure (1990)",
            4: "Gadget Boy &amp; Heather (1995)",
            5: "Samurai Jack (2001 &ndash; 2004)"
        },
        "answer": 1,
        "answer-exp": "The Fonz and the Happy Days Gang (1980 - 1982) was a Hanna-Barbera animated television series. It was a spin-off of Happy Days and included three of its characters, The Fonz (Henry Winkler), Richie Cunningham (Ron Howard), and Ralph Malph (Donny Most). These characters were joined by an anthropomorphic dog, Mr. Cool, and a girl from the future, Cupcake. The group travel through history in a time machine, trying to get back to 1957 Milwaukee."
    },
    16: {
        "icon": "train",
        "question": "<strong>Time Express (1979)</strong> was a television show about a train that took people on trips through time. Who starred in the show?",
        "options": {
            1: "William Shatner",
            2: "Alan Alda",
            3: "Vincent Price",
            4: "Henry Winkler",
            5: "Danny DeVito"
        },
        "answer": 3,
        "answer-exp": "Time Express was a short-lived television anthology series that was a time travel version of similar anothology shows like Love Boat or Fantasy Island. The train's husband (Vincent Price) and wife hosts would shepard its passengers back in time to relive a crucial point in their lives."
    },
    17: {
        "icon": "rocket",
        "question": "In the <strong>Futurama (1999 - 2013)</strong> episode \"Roswell That Ends Well\" the main character, Fry, sleeps with his grandmother and ends up becoming his own grandfather. Time travel that results in someone becoming their own ancestor is an example of what concept?",
        "options": {
            1: "the butterfly effect",
            2: "a predestination paradox",
            3: "temporal merging",
            4: "quantum entanglement",
            5: "multiple universe theory"
        },
        "answer": 2,
        "answer-exp": "A predestination paradox (also known as a causality loop) is when causation between two or more events form a loop. For example, Fry being his own ancestor is a cause of his own existence, but his existence is required for him to time travel and become his own ancestor."
    },
    18: {
        "icon": "newspaper-o",
        "question": "Which writer was editor of The Sun newspaper and is often credited with being the first to use several science fiction ideas, including time travel in his short stories?",
        "options": {
            1: "Charles Anderson Dana",
            2: "Mark Twain",
            3: "Edward Page Mitchell",
            4: "Charles Dickens",
            5: "Herbert George Wells"
        },
        "answer": 3,
        "answer-exp": "Edward Page Mitchell (1852 - 1927) was a short story writer and editor of a New York newspaper. Mitchell's stories incorporated a number of science fiction concepts before they were used in other works, including stories involving an invisible man in The Crystal Man (1881), time travel in The Clock that Went Backward (1881), faster-than-light travel in The Tachypomp (1874), a thinking computer and a cyborg in The Ablest Man in the World (1879), teleportation in The Man without a Body (1877), and mind transfer in Exchanging Their Souls (1877)."
    },
    19: {
        "icon": "file-text-o",
        "question": "Who coined the term \"time machine\" to describe a mechanism used to transport a traveller through time?",
        "options": {
            1: "Jules Verne",
            2: "Mark Twain",
            3: "William Shakespere",
            4: "Washington Irving",
            5: "Herbert George Wells"
        },
        "answer": 5,
        "answer-exp": "H.G. WELLS (1866 - 1946) was the author of The Time Machine (1895), in which a scientist in Victorian England builds a machine to travel through time. Wells is credited with coining the term \"time machine\" in this work."

    },
    20: {
        "icon": "newspaper-o",
        "question": "What was the name of the television series (1996 - 2000) in which the main character receives a newspaper from one day in the future every day?",
        "options": {
            1: "Tomorrow's Tales",
            2: "The Paradox Papers",
            3: "Next Day News",
            4: "The Day to Come",
            5: "Early Edition"
        },
        "answer": 5,
        "answer-exp": "Early Edition (1996 - 2000) followed the adventures of Gary Hobson (Kyle Chandler) who mysteriously receives the Chicago Sun-Times newspaper the day before it is actually published, and who uses this knowledge to prevent terrible events contained in its pages."

    }
};

/*



*/






